SAM MACINTYRE

I'm a skilled, graphic designer who loves working with brands to design stand out packaging.

An inquisitive problem solver, my experience covers all stages of the design process from concept development to final print, as well as providing art direction & overall project & stakeholder management. I successfully drive projects, producing high quality, creative designs with some of the biggest names in food, drinks & retail around the world.

GET IN TOUCH

+44 (0) 7511 454 074

hello@sammacintyre.com linkedin.com/in/sammacintyre

PORTFOLIO

sammacintyre.com

EXPERIENCE

Packaging Graphic Designer

Target Australia, Retail, target.com.au

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Melbourne, Australia

Worked with teams across the business developing apparel and beauty packaging.

- Successfully managed the roll out of own brand beauty packaging redesign, building out the style guide & artwork templates across various pack formats & providing art direction & management of internal stakeholder approvals for upwards of 200 SKUs across 6 local suppliers.
- Simplified Target Main Range sew-in labels, resulting in consistency in size & colour across all apparel departments, & reducing label job numbers in the system by 90% allowing for more efficient allocation to products & cost savings when forecasting.
- Refreshed MAXX brand packaging in children's underwear & sleep, & extended packaging artwork into socks contributing to 75% increase in department sales vs LY.

Freelance Graphic Designer

Various Clients - Examples below

Mar. 2019 - Jan. 2020

Melbourne, Australia

- APR Creative Creative Agency, aprcreative.com.au
 Regular freelance support across everything from packaging concept development, print layout design, creation of digital assets & motion graphics.
- The Animals Creative Ad Agency, theanimals.com.au Creation & roll-out of key visuals across print & digital.
- Moose Toys Toy Industry, moosetoys.com/au
 Assisted packaging concept development for Treasure X Fire vs Ice & Treasure X Aliens.

Graphic Designer

Mar. 2016 - Dec. 2018

Lightbody Ventures, Food Industry, lightbodyventures.com

Glasgow, UK

Designed packaging & sales support material for licensed food products across various high profile brands.

- Was brand guardian for all packaging & sales support material for the \$15m Hershey Company licensed bakery product range in the USA. I designed all artwork & managed approvals with Hershey to ensure everything adhered to their strict brand guidelines.
- Designed packaging for Disney Kitchen toddler snacking range, contributing to attainment of Mumsnet Rated license (a first for the toddler snacking category) & The Grocer New Product Award for "Apple Fruity Bakes".
- Introduced artwork sign off procedure to ensure output was 100% accurate & had always been sighted by the appropriate parties before going to print.

1

EXPERIENCE

Packaging Technologist

Sep. 2015 - Mar. 2016

Beam Suntory UK Ltd, Whisky Industry, beamsuntory.com

Glasgow, UK

Assisted the development of packaging components for Scotch Whisky brands.

- Identified inconsistencies in typesetting across Laphroaig Lore packaging. Organised meetings between the separate agencies working on the packaging to ensure text was consistent across all SKUs.
- Organised bottling line trial for Laphroaig Lore, the outcome of which allowed critical decisions to be made on the pack format & the project to be delivered on time.
- Coordinated early supplier meetings & built out packaging development critical paths, assisting in the successful delivery of the high value Black Bowmore 50 Year Old whisky - worth £16,000 per bottle.

Product Designer

Oct. 2014 - Jul. 2015

Worlds Apart (now Moose Toys UK), Children's Products

Newquay, UK

Designed artwork using licensed style guides for various children's products including pop-up tents & ReadyBed® blow up beds. Licenses worked with included Disney Frozen, Despicable Me & Paw Patrol.

EDUCATION

MEng (Hons) Product Design Engineering, 2:1

University of Glasgow / The Glasgow School of Art